# **Sher Ahmed Durrani**

•

**1** +92 334-2000647; +92 342-8000272

Sherahmed.durrani@gmail.com / sher.ahmad@siss.uol.edu.pk

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sher-ahmed-61a90353/

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I have research experience and publication in politics and International Relations with particular focus on South Asian Studies. Current research is on Kabul Delhi-Nexus and its implication for the regional peace. South Asian politics will be continued beyond my research work. Pakistan-China relations will also be of great interest.

# ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

#### M.Phil. Political Science

[September2015–2018]

University of Management and Technology (UMT), Lahore, Pakistan

CGPA 3.85/4.0 (course work) and 3.67/4.0(Comprehensive)

<u>Dissertation Topic</u>: "Kabul Delhi-Nexus (The dilemma of Afghan Peace Process and Political Responses to the Security Environment in Post 9/11 Scenario)"

<u>Major Courses</u>: Foreign Policy Analysis: Conflict and Conflict Resolution; Governance and Democracy in South Asia; Research Methodology in Social Science

#### **International Relations, Masters**

[2013– November 2015]

University of Baluchistan (UOB) Quetta, Pakistan

Second division

<u>Major Subjects</u>: Theories of International Relations, Diplomacy, Foreign policy, Security studies, Research Methodology; Contemporary Global Issues; International Security, Diplomacy, Strategic studies.

#### **Political Science, Bachelor of Arts**

[2011 – October2013]

University of Baluchistan, Quetta, Pakistan

Second division

<u>Major Subjects</u>: Diplomatic History of the World, Pakistan's Foreign Policy, Globalization, International Law, Human Rights, Foreign Policies of Major Power (United States, Russia and China), Terrorism& Counterterrorism, Issues in World Politics, Conflict and Conflict Resolution. Sociology

Minor Subjects: Political Science and Social Work.

#### I.C.S, Government Degree Collage Loralai (Intermediate)

[September2009 - August2011

Obtained Percentage65%

#### Science, Secondary Education (BISE) (Matriculation)

[March 2005–August2007]

Tameer-i- Nau Public High School, Lorelai

# **FELLOWSHIPS AND GRANTS**

#### **Individual Research Fellowship**

Research Fellow (University of Education Lahore), Research fellow to University of Education,
 Collage Road Branch Lahore under the *Prime Minister Internship program* (Applied Jan 2017;
 Status: Awarded in April 2017

#### Merit Scholarship/Grants

- University of Management and Technology, Lahore
- (Status: Awarded in M.Phil. from June 2017 to 2018)

# CERTIFICATES/WORKSHOPS/ COURSE(S)

Certificate of Participation in **Easy Systematic Literature Review Techniques Workshop**, organized by the Chief Librarian, UMT *Lahore University Joher Town Campus* from 16 March 2017 to 17 marches 2017.

**Certificate of Completion** in US Pakistan Interreligious Consortium For "Promoting Peace and Harmony Globally," organized by the *University of Management and Technology*, supported by a grant from the U.S. Department of State on Wednesday, May 03, 2017

**Certificate of Attendance in NGO Capacity Building and Good Practices Training** organized by *Greencare's Associates UK*, Lahore-Pakistan (from September 16-18 2015).

**Certificate of** Participation in **English Skills Course** organized by *BETS (British Education and Training Programme)*, Lahore Pakistan

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Serving at The University of Lahore as a Lecturer

#### JOB DESCRIPTION – LECTURER

#### **Overall Purpose:**

To work collaboratively as part of a team of academic, technical and administrative colleagues. To facilitate learning in the University to the highest quality through teaching, administration and academic advisory work and ensure an outstanding student learning experience. Contribute to curriculum development and to the research / knowledge transfer profile of the University, through high quality research, publication and/or professional practice.

# **Teaching and Learning**

To contribute to learning, teaching, assessment and ongoing curriculum development by
involvement as part of a team through:
☐ The design, preparation and development of module teaching materials;
$\Box$ The provision of high quality teaching, assessment and support for students' learning on designated modules at all levels;
$\Box$ The delivery of modules through lectures, seminars, workshops, tutorials and other learning situations;
$\Box$ participating in the quality enhancement of learning, teaching and assessment activities within the framework of the University's quality enhancement processes and assessment regulations;
□ liaise closely with teaching, technical and administrative staff as appropriate to ensure a quality teaching and learning environment;

$\Box$ adopting a reflective approach towards the development of own practice;
$\Box$ giving effective advice, guidance and feedback to students to support their academic progress and referring students to support services as appropriate;
☐ The management of own teaching and administrative activities.
Research, Scholarship and Consultancy
☐ To undertake personal research and/or scholarly activities and/or consultancy contributing to the Campus and University profile.
☐ To supervise students' scholarship and research activities.
☐ To undertake continuous professional development and participate in staff development and training activities to update and enhance skills.
General Functions
☐ To participate in the University staff appraisal scheme and other relevant activities.
☐ To attend meetings and committees as appropriate/as requested by the Head of Campus.

# **Curriculum Development**

Contribute to and assist in curriculum development and in reviewing and reforming modules, subjects and programmes with higher Education authority.

# 1. Lead BRSP, as M&E/Compliance Officer, In Planning Monitoring, Evaluation & Research (PMER) Section (BRACE- European Union) (2018-2020)

# **Specific Responsibilities:**

- Develop, formulate and implement the quarterly and annual M&E Plans, in coordination with team of assigned FU.
- Support PMER Coordinator in defining, implementing and reporting on the key project performance indicators (KPI) as well as monitoring against specific indicators throughout the duration of the projects.
- Monitor project's specific activities at field and ensure timely sharing of best practices and lessons learnt with the management and concerned FU team.
- Ensure compliances in Participatory Development Planning processes at village and UC level (i.e. development of V/UCDPs).
- Verification of sub-granting documentation of IGGs, CIF and CPIs in compliance with specific guidelines of the programme.
- Develop potential success stories, case studies to highlight projects' outcome and impact of interventions.
- Assess outcome/impact of project activities on vulnerable groups i.e. children, women, disables and minorities.
- Regular interactions with beneficiaries and CIs to record their feedback, assessing their performance by applying standardized tools such as institutional maturity index and rapid assessment exercises.
- Assist in developing data collection formats and undertake regular data collection on all project component, analyze data and prepare regular updates/reports of the progress for the management.
- Identify and report noncompliance of BRSP's policies and procedures along with the conditions defined by the donor on regular basis.
- Identify and gather a database of information required to be used for carrying out the situation analysis/baselines and identification of project requirements.

- Support PMER Coordinator to ensure that donor(s) and Senior Management's data queries are addressed in an accurate and timely manner.
- Keep him/herself updated with sectorial plans, Field Unit development plans, performance against sectorial indicators and government's priorities.
- Identify strengths and weaknesses in existing data collection and management systems and propose solutions.
- Ensure its proper implementation of MISs and provide feedback on its effective functioning.
- Review and analyze monthly/quarterly progress reports and ensure the reports are presenting accurate information on outputs, outcomes, best practices and challenges.
- Guide and coach the M&E/MIS Assistant in performing his/her duties; and effective utilization of his/her services in on-field monitoring, verification of beneficiaries, data gathering and Reviewing MoVs of project interventions.

# **Worked as Area Sales Manager in PTCL**

# (Pakistan Telecommunications limited), Lahore (2016-2018)

# Responsibilities

- Providing organizational capacity building programs by guiding internal development of the organization,
- Drafting new plans for achieving measurable and sustainable results, respectively.
- Conducting orientation training to the new employees.
- Managing all the activities of Sales;
- Addressing complains of the customers and reviewers personally.
- Promoting better co-ordination among different departments of the organization.
- Ensures that direct area sales team achieves assigned monthly, quarterly and annual sales targets for all brands according to agreed quality benchmark. The role will lead a team of TSMs, OSS and Exchanges and all direct channels inducted from time to time.
- He will visit all OSS according to a route and ensure at least 01 visit to each Point of sales every month.
- Ensures implementation of sales planning for all PTCL brands in the area across all direct channels. This will focus on making OSS, Exchanges, Ufone franchise selling our brands etc. more efficient through scientific performance management support.
- Ensures ample stock of all brands for standardized distribution in agreed direct channels.
- Ensures that all points of sale within area are well managed according to Trade Marketing strategy and ensuring agreed service level, productivity and out of stock.
- Ensuring that all direct channels managers and their staff is well trained and monitored to deliver assigned jobs efficiently.
- Ensuring agreed score in regional and area score cards.
- Ensure adherence to all company principles and policies.
- Ensure continuous improvement

# Worked as Internee in NACTA (National Counter Terrorism Authority)

#### Islamabad (Jun2018-Dec2018)

# Responsibilities

- Develops the strategy and vision to position a project from inception through completion
- Creates teams and collaborations that understand the project's direction.
- Communicates direction through words or actions to inspire team members to reach goals.
- Being a Research Fellow also responsible for planning and budgeting. The Research Fellow manages a departmental sub-function within a broader departmental function.
- Creates functional strategies and specific objectives for the sub-function and develops security/policies/procedures to support the functional infrastructure.
- Deep knowledge of the managed sub-function and solid knowledge of the overall departmental function.
- 2. Worked as Academic Coordinator in Lahore Leads University (2015)
- 3. Served as an Instructor in Private Collages for 2 years (part time)

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

- The Emergence of Crude Nationalism
- Afghanistan and Geopolitics of Great Game
- India's Foreign Policy and its Relations with Afghanistan
- Pakistan's Foreign Relations
- Power play between US and China in Asia
- Pakistan-China Relations in the Post 9/11 Era.
- Rise of China in the Post-Cold War Era.
- India-US Strategic Alliance in the Post-9/11 era
- South Asian and Balance-of-Power Dynamics
- Central Asia and Power Competition
- Theories of International Relations

# PROFESSIONAL CONFERENCE(S)/WORKSHOP(S) ATTENDED

- Confidence Building Measures in South Asia, Conference attended at Centre for South Asian Studies, University of the Punjab, Lahore, Pakistan. 25 November 2015.
- Sino-India Relations: Implications for Pakistan by Prof. Dr XiaoJianming
  1-day Seminar held at Center of South Asian Studies, University of Punjab, Pakistan.
  07 February 2015.
- **60 Years of Pakistan-China Relations: Challenges, Trends &Approaches,**A seminar jointly organized by Institute of Policy Study (IPS) Islamabad and Pakistan Study Center (PSC), Sichuan University, Chengdu-China. IPS, Islamabad 11-12 April 2017.

# SKILLSAND COMPETENCIES

Languages: English, Urdu, Pashto

**Administration:** Performed administrative duties as class representative at college and

university levels.

**Leadership Skills**: Effective team leader with exceptional interpersonal skills.

Founded "Pen Power Society" for social science researchers having

expertise in different disciplines.

**Instructional skills:** Good instructional skills

Technical Expertise: NVIVO, End notes, ODK, Microsoft office (Word, PowerPoint), Internet, e-

mail, Team Viewer, Google Hangout, Virtual Conferencing CRM,

Networking, A+

Map projection: (Having command over General Knowledge and Geo-Politics among

Nations)

References will be furnished upon request.